export const quiz = [
  {
    sport: "Football",
    id: 1,
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Who won the FIFA World Cup in 2018?",
        options: ["Brazil", "Germany", "France"],
        correctAnswer: "France"
      },
      {
        question: "Which club won the UEFA Champions League in 2020?",
        options: ["Bayern Munich", "Liverpool", "Real Madrid"],
        correctAnswer: "Bayern Munich"
      },
      {
        question: "Who is the all-time top scorer in La Liga history?",
        options: ["Ronaldo", "Messi", "Raúl"],
        correctAnswer: "Messi"
      },
      {
        question: "What event is known as the \"Final Four\"?",
        options: ["World Cup", "Champions League", "Confederations Cup"],
        correctAnswer: "Champions League"
      },
      {
        question: "Which club has the most Premier League titles?",
        options: ["Manchester United", "Chelsea", "Arsenal"],
        correctAnswer: "Manchester United"
      },
      {
        question: "Who holds the record for the most goals in a single Premier League season?",
        options: ["Alan Shearer", "Mohamed Salah", "Thierry Henry"],
        correctAnswer: "Mohamed Salah"
      },
      {
        question: "Which country hosted the 1994 FIFA World Cup?",
        options: ["Italy", "United States", "France"],
        correctAnswer: "United States"
      },
      {
        question: "Who is known as the \"King of Football\"?",
        options: ["Diego Maradona", "Pelé", "Johan Cruyff"],
        correctAnswer: "Pelé"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the maximum number of players allowed on the field for one team in football?",
        options: ["10", "11", "12"],
        correctAnswer: "11"
      },
      {
        question: "Which tournament is considered the most prestigious club competition in Europe?",
        options: ["UEFA Champions League", "Europa League", "UEFA Super Cup"],
        correctAnswer: "UEFA Champions League"
      }
    ],
    sportsmanFact: "Cristiano Ronaldo: Portuguese footballer Cristiano Ronaldo is considered one of the greatest players in the history of football. Known for his incredible athleticism, powerful shots, and goal-scoring ability, he has won five Ballon d'Or awards and has set numerous records, including being the all-time leading scorer in the UEFA Champions League. Ronaldo has had successful spells at clubs like Manchester United, Real Madrid, and Juventus, and continues to perform at a high level in international competitions with the Portuguese national team.",
    adviceOnLoss: "Don't be discouraged! Football is a complex sport with a rich history. Keep watching matches, learning about different leagues and players, and you'll improve your knowledge in no time."
  },
  {
    sport: "Basketball",
    id: 2,
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Who is known as the \"Greatest of All Time\" in basketball?",
        options: ["Michael Jordan", "LeBron James", "Kobe Bryant"],
        correctAnswer: "Michael Jordan"
      },
      {
        question: "How many points is a three-pointer worth in the NBA?",
        options: ["1", "2", "3"],
        correctAnswer: "3"
      },
      {
        question: "Which team has won the most NBA championships?",
        options: ["Miami Heat", "Boston Celtics", "Los Angeles Lakers"],
        correctAnswer: "Boston Celtics"
      },
      {
        question: "Who holds the record for the most points scored in a single NBA game?",
        options: ["Wilt Chamberlain", "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar", "Kobe Bryant"],
        correctAnswer: "Wilt Chamberlain"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the length of an NBA basketball court?",
        options: ["90 feet", "94 feet", "100 feet"],
        correctAnswer: "94 feet"
      },
      {
        question: "Who won the NBA MVP award in 2021?",
        options: ["Nikola Jokić", "Giannis Antetokounmpo", "Kevin Durant"],
        correctAnswer: "Nikola Jokić"
      },
      {
        question: "What year was the NBA founded?",
        options: ["1946", "1950", "1949"],
        correctAnswer: "1949"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the championship series in the NBA?",
        options: ["NBA Finals", "NBA Championship", "NBA Playoffs"],
        correctAnswer: "NBA Championship"
      },
      {
        question: "How many players are on the court for one team during a basketball game?",
        options: ["5", "5", "6"],
        correctAnswer: "5"
      },
      {
        question: "Which country won the gold medal in basketball at the 2008 Olympics?",
        options: ["United States", "Spain", "Argentina"],
        correctAnswer: "United States"
      }
    ],
    sportsmanFact: "LeBron James: American basketball player LeBron James is one of the most influential athletes of his generation. He has won four NBA championships and has been named NBA Finals MVP four times. Known for his versatility, basketball IQ, and leadership both on and off the court, LeBron has broken numerous records and has consistently been among the league's top scorers. His impact extends beyond basketball, as he is also a prominent advocate for social justice and education initiatives.",
    adviceOnLoss: "Keep your head up! Basketball knowledge comes with time. Watch more NBA games, learn about different playing positions, and study the greats of the game to boost your understanding."
  },
  {
    sport: "Tennis",
    id: 3,
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Who has won the most Grand Slam titles in men's singles?",
        options: ["Roger Federer", "Rafael Nadal", "Novak Djokovic"],
        correctAnswer: "Roger Federer"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the tournament held at Wimbledon?",
        options: ["French Open", "Wimbledon", "US Open"],
        correctAnswer: "Wimbledon"
      },
      {
        question: "Who was the first woman to win a Grand Slam?",
        options: ["Maureen Connolly", "Serena Williams", "Chris Evert"],
        correctAnswer: "Maureen Connolly"
      },
      {
        question: "How many sets are played in a typical Grand Slam match?",
        options: ["3", "5", "7"],
        correctAnswer: "5"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the surface of the French Open?",
        options: ["Clay", "Grass", "Hard"],
        correctAnswer: "Clay"
      },
      {
        question: "Who won the Wimbledon Men's Singles title in 2019?",
        options: ["Roger Federer", "Novak Djokovic", "Rafael Nadal"],
        correctAnswer: "Novak Djokovic"
      },
      {
        question: "Which country hosts the Australian Open?",
        options: ["Australia", "United States", "England"],
        correctAnswer: "Australia"
      },
      {
        question: "Who is known for his powerful serve and winning the US Open in 2004?",
        options: ["Andy Roddick", "Roger Federer", "Lleyton Hewitt"],
        correctAnswer: "Roger Federer"
      },
      {
        question: "How many Grand Slam tournaments are there each year?",
        options: ["4", "3", "5"],
        correctAnswer: "4"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the term for winning all four Grand Slam tournaments in a calendar year?",
        options: ["Grand Slam", "Golden Slam", "Triple Crown"],
        correctAnswer: "Grand Slam"
      }
    ],
    sportsmanFact: "Serena Williams: American tennis player Serena Williams is regarded as one of the greatest female athletes of all time. She has won 23 Grand Slam singles titles, the most in the Open Era, and is known for her powerful serve, exceptional athleticism, and mental toughness. Williams has broken barriers in tennis and has been an inspiration for many aspiring athletes around the world. Her success on the court has made her a global icon.",
    adviceOnLoss: "Don't let this result discourage you! Tennis has many nuances. Try watching more Grand Slam tournaments and learning about the different court surfaces to improve your knowledge."
  },
  {
    sport: "Athletics",
    id: 4,
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the distance of a marathon?",
        options: ["26.2 miles", "24.3 miles", "25 miles"],
        correctAnswer: "26.2 miles"
      },
      {
        question: "Who holds the world record for the 100m sprint?",
        options: ["Usain Bolt", "Carl Lewis", "Justin Gatlin"],
        correctAnswer: "Usain Bolt"
      },
      {
        question: "In which year did the Olympic Games first include women's events?",
        options: ["1900", "1928", "1936"],
        correctAnswer: "1928"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the standard height of a high jump bar in men's competitions?",
        options: ["1.90 meters", "1.70 meters", "2.40 meters"],
        correctAnswer: "2.40 meters"
      },
      {
        question: "How many events are in a decathlon?",
        options: ["10", "10", "15"],
        correctAnswer: "10"
      },
      {
        question: "Which event involves throwing a spear?",
        options: ["Javelin", "Shot Put", "Discus"],
        correctAnswer: "Javelin"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the track and field competition held every four years?",
        options: ["Olympics", "World Championships", "Commonwealth Games"],
        correctAnswer: "Olympics"
      },
      {
        question: "Who is known as the \"Fastest Woman in the World\"?",
        options: ["Florence Griffith-Joyner", "Marion Jones", "Allyson Felix"],
        correctAnswer: "Marion Jones"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the longest distance in track and field?",
        options: ["10,000 meters", "5,000 meters", "3,000 meters"],
        correctAnswer: "10,000 meters"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the event that combines running, jumping, and throwing?",
        options: ["Track and Field", "Triathlon", "Heptathlon"],
        correctAnswer: "Track and Field"
      }
    ],
    sportsmanFact: "Carl Lewis: American track and field athlete Carl Lewis is a legendary figure in athletics, having won nine Olympic gold medals and numerous World Championship titles. He excelled in sprints and long jump events and was known for his versatility and dominance in various competitions. Lewis's success spanned over a decade, and he is remembered not only for his achievements but also for his role in popularizing athletics in the United States.",
    adviceOnLoss: "Athletics covers a wide range of events. Don't worry if you didn't score high this time. Focus on learning about different track and field disciplines and famous athletes to improve your knowledge."
  },
  {
    sport: "Swimming",
    id: 5,
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the fastest stroke in competitive swimming?",
        options: ["Freestyle", "Breaststroke", "Backstroke"],
        correctAnswer: "Freestyle"
      },
      {
        question: "How many meters is an Olympic swimming pool?",
        options: ["25 meters", "50 meters", "100 meters"],
        correctAnswer: "50 meters"
      },
      {
        question: "Who holds the world record for the men's 100m freestyle?",
        options: ["Michael Phelps", "César Cielo", "Ian Thorpe"],
        correctAnswer: "César Cielo"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the swimming competition held every two years?",
        options: ["World Championships", "Olympics", "Pan Pacific Championships"],
        correctAnswer: "World Championships"
      },
      {
        question: "How many strokes are used in the individual medley?",
        options: ["2", "4", "3"],
        correctAnswer: "4"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the event where swimmers compete in a series of heats?",
        options: ["Preliminary heats", "Finals", "Relays"],
        correctAnswer: "Preliminary heats"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the distance of the Olympic marathon swim?",
        options: ["5 km", "10 km", "15 km"],
        correctAnswer: "10 km"
      },
      {
        question: "Who is the most decorated Olympian of all time?",
        options: ["Michael Phelps", "Mark Spitz", "Ryan Lochte"],
        correctAnswer: "Michael Phelps"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the stroke where swimmers lie on their back?",
        options: ["Butterfly", "Freestyle", "Backstroke"],
        correctAnswer: "Backstroke"
      },
      {
        question: "How many gold medals did Michael Phelps win in the 2008 Beijing Olympics?",
        options: ["6", "7", "8"],
        correctAnswer: "8"
      }
    ],
    sportsmanFact: "Katie Ledecky: American swimmer Katie Ledecky is one of the most successful female swimmers in history. She has won multiple Olympic gold medals and world championships in long-distance freestyle events. Known for her exceptional endurance and technique, Ledecky has set numerous world records, solidifying her status as a dominant force in competitive swimming. Her achievements have inspired a new generation of swimmers.",
    adviceOnLoss: "Swimming has many techniques and events to learn about. Keep diving into the subject! Watch swimming competitions, learn about different strokes, and study famous swimmers to boost your knowledge."
  },
  {
    sport: "Formula 1 Racing",
    id: 6,
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Who holds the record for the most Formula 1 World Championships?",
        options: ["Lewis Hamilton", "Michael Schumacher", "Ayrton Senna"],
        correctAnswer: "Lewis Hamilton"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the race held annually in Monaco?",
        options: ["Monaco Grand Prix", "British Grand Prix", "Italian Grand Prix"],
        correctAnswer: "Monaco Grand Prix"
      },
      {
        question: "How many teams compete in a Formula 1 race?",
        options: ["10", "11", "12"],
        correctAnswer: "11"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the fastest speed recorded during a Formula 1 race?",
        options: ["300 km/h", "372 km/h", "350 km/h"],
        correctAnswer: "372 km/h"
      },
      {
        question: "Which driver has the most pole positions in Formula 1 history?",
        options: ["Lewis Hamilton", "Michael Schumacher", "Sebastian Vettel"],
        correctAnswer: "Lewis Hamilton"
      },
      {
        question: "How many laps are in a typical Formula 1 race?",
        options: ["40", "60", "70"],
        correctAnswer: "60"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the trophy awarded to the Formula 1 World Champion?",
        options: ["The Pirelli Trophy", "The World Championship Trophy", "The Constructor's Trophy"],
        correctAnswer: "The World Championship Trophy"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the primary tire supplier for Formula 1?",
        options: ["Bridgestone", "Pirelli", "Michelin"],
        correctAnswer: "Pirelli"
      },
      {
        question: "Who won the 2021 Formula 1 World Championship?",
        options: ["Lewis Hamilton", "Max Verstappen", "Valtteri Bottas"],
        correctAnswer: "Max Verstappen"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the team owned by Ferrari?",
        options: ["Scuderia Ferrari", "Red Bull Racing", "McLaren"],
        correctAnswer: "Scuderia Ferrari"
      }
    ],
    sportsmanFact: "Michael Schumacher: German driver Michael Schumacher is one of the most successful Formula 1 drivers of all time. He won seven World Championships and holds numerous records, including the most race wins in F1 history at the time of his retirement. Schumacher was known for his fierce competitiveness, precision, and unparalleled driving skill, making him a legend in the world of motorsports.",
    adviceOnLoss: "Formula 1 is a complex sport with lots of technical details. Don't be discouraged! Watch more races, learn about the teams and their strategies, and you'll soon become an F1 expert."
  },
  {
    sport: "Winter Sports",
    id: 7,
    questions: [
      {
        question: "Which country hosted the 2014 Winter Olympics?",
        options: ["Vancouver", "Pyeongchang", "Sochi"],
        correctAnswer: "Sochi"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the distance of the men's Olympic ski jump?",
        options: ["100 meters", "120 meters", "150 meters"],
        correctAnswer: "120 meters"
      },
      {
        question: "Who is the most decorated Winter Olympian of all time?",
        options: ["Torvill and Dean", "Marit Bjørgen", "Apolo Anton Ohno"],
        correctAnswer: "Marit Bjørgen"
      },
      {
        question: "What sport combines skiing and shooting?",
        options: ["Biathlon", "Nordic Combined", "Ski Cross"],
        correctAnswer: "Biathlon"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the Olympic sport played on ice with stones?",
        options: ["Ice Hockey", "Figure Skating", "Curling"],
        correctAnswer: "Curling"
      },
      {
        question: "How many events are in the Winter Olympics?",
        options: ["100", "15", "20"],
        correctAnswer: "15"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the term for a race in which skiers navigate a series of gates?",
        options: ["Slalom", "Giant Slalom", "Downhill"],
        correctAnswer: "Giant Slalom"
      },
      {
        question: "Which country has the most gold medals in Winter Olympics history?",
        options: ["Germany", "Norway", "United States"],
        correctAnswer: "Norway"
      },
      {
        question: "In which sport do athletes perform jumps and spins on ice?",
        options: ["Figure Skating", "Short Track Speed Skating", "Ice Dancing"],
        correctAnswer: "Figure Skating"
      },
      {
        question: "How many players are on a typical ice hockey team?",
        options: ["5", "6", "7"],
        correctAnswer: "6"
      }
    ],
    sportsmanFact: "Marit Bjørgen: Norwegian cross-country skier Marit Bjørgen is one of the most decorated winter sports athletes in history. With 15 Olympic medals, including eight golds, and numerous World Championship titles, she is known for her incredible endurance and versatility across different distances. Bjørgen's dominance in cross-country skiing has made her a national hero in Norway and an inspiration to winter sports athletes worldwide.",
    adviceOnLoss: "Winter sports cover a wide variety of disciplines. Keep your spirits high and continue learning! Watch winter Olympics events and read about different winter sports to improve your knowledge."
  },
  {
    sport: "Cycling",
    id: 8,
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the longest professional cycling race?",
        options: ["Tour de France", "Giro d'Italia", "Vuelta a España"],
        correctAnswer: "Tour de France"
      },
      {
        question: "Who holds the record for the most Tour de France victories?",
        options: ["Miguel Indurain", "Lance Armstrong", "Bernard Hinault"],
        correctAnswer: "Lance Armstrong"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the main color of the leader's jersey in the Tour de France?",
        options: ["Green", "White", "Yellow"],
        correctAnswer: "Yellow"
      },
      {
        question: "Which cycling event is known for its mountainous terrain?",
        options: ["Giro d'Italia", "Tour de France", "Vuelta a España"],
        correctAnswer: "Giro d'Italia"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the cycling race held in Italy every May?",
        options: ["Tour de France", "Vuelta a España", "Giro d'Italia"],
        correctAnswer: "Giro d'Italia"
      },
      {
        question: "Who is known as the \"Cannibal\" in cycling?",
        options: ["Miguel Indurain", "Eddy Merckx", "Fausto Coppi"],
        correctAnswer: "Eddy Merckx"
      },
      {
        question: "How long is the Tour de France?",
        options: ["2 weeks", "3 weeks", "4 weeks"],
        correctAnswer: "3 weeks"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the primary discipline of cycling that focuses on road racing?",
        options: ["Mountain Biking", "Road Cycling", "BMX"],
        correctAnswer: "Road Cycling"
      },
      {
        question: "Which country is known for hosting the famous race \"Paris-Roubaix\"?",
        options: ["Belgium", "France", "Netherlands"],
        correctAnswer: "France"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the cycling technique where riders draft behind each other?",
        options: ["Sprinting", "Slipstreaming", "Climbing"],
        correctAnswer: "Slipstreaming"
      }
    ],
    sportsmanFact: "Lance Armstrong: American cyclist Lance Armstrong is known for his seven consecutive Tour de France victories, although his legacy has been marred by doping controversies. Despite the controversies, his impact on the sport and his role in raising awareness for cancer through his Livestrong foundation made him a prominent figure in cycling. His journey from a cancer survivor to a champion cyclist remains a significant part of his story.",
    adviceOnLoss: "Cycling has a rich history and many different events. Don't worry about this result! Watch more cycling tours, learn about different types of races, and study famous cyclists to enhance your knowledge."
  },
  {
    sport: "Gymnastics",
    id: 9,
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the highest score a gymnast can achieve in a routine?",
        options: ["10.0", "10.0 (perfect score)", "9.5"],
        correctAnswer: "10.0 (perfect score)"
      },
      {
        question: "Which Olympic event features the floor exercise?",
        options: ["Artistic Gymnastics", "Rhythmic Gymnastics", "Trampoline"],
        correctAnswer: "Artistic Gymnastics"
      },
      {
        question: "Who is considered the greatest gymnast of all time?",
        options: ["Nadia Comăneci", "Simone Biles", "Mary Lou Retton"],
        correctAnswer: "Simone Biles"
      },
      {
        question: "What apparatus is used for vaulting?",
        options: ["Vault", "Balance Beam", "Floor"],
        correctAnswer: "Vault"
      },
      {
        question: "How many events are in artistic gymnastics for women?",
        options: ["4", "4", "6"],
        correctAnswer: "4"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the routine performed on the balance beam?",
        options: ["Floor Exercise", "Balance Beam Routine", "Vault Routine"],
        correctAnswer: "Balance Beam Routine"
      },
      {
        question: "Which country has dominated women's gymnastics in the Olympics?",
        options: ["Russia", "United States", "China"],
        correctAnswer: "United States"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the term for a combination of gymnastic elements performed in a routine?",
        options: ["Skill", "Sequence", "Routine"],
        correctAnswer: "Routine"
      },
      {
        question: "Who is known for her \"Biles\" skill in gymnastics?",
        options: ["Nadia Comăneci", "Simone Biles", "Gabby Douglas"],
        correctAnswer: "Simone Biles"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the Olympic event that includes multiple apparatus?",
        options: ["All-Around", "Individual Event", "Team Competition"],
        correctAnswer: "All-Around"
      }
    ],
    sportsmanFact: "Simone Biles: American gymnast Simone Biles is a four-time Olympic gold medalist and widely considered one of the greatest gymnasts of all time. Known for her incredible athleticism and groundbreaking skills, Biles has won numerous World Championship titles and has revolutionized the sport with her innovative routines. Her advocacy for mental health has also sparked important conversations within and beyond the sports community.",
    adviceOnLoss: "Gymnastics is a complex sport with many events and techniques. Keep your chin up! Watch more gymnastics competitions, learn about different apparatus, and study famous gymnasts to improve your score next time."
  },
  {
    sport: "Motorsports",
    id: 10,
    questions: [
      {
        question: "What is the most prestigious race in motorsports?",
        options: ["Le Mans 24 Hours", "Monaco Grand Prix", "Daytona 500"],
        correctAnswer: "Monaco Grand Prix"
      },
      {
        question: "Who holds the record for the most wins in Formula 1?",
        options: ["Michael Schumacher", "Lewis Hamilton", "Ayrton Senna"],
        correctAnswer: "Lewis Hamilton"
      },
      {
        question: "What type of racing involves NASCAR?",
        options: ["Stock Car Racing", "Open-Wheel Racing", "Rally Racing"],
        correctAnswer: "Stock Car Racing"
      },
      {
        question: "Which race is known as \"The Great American Race\"?",
        options: ["Indianapolis 500", "Daytona 500", "Talladega 500"],
        correctAnswer: "Daytona 500"
      },
      {
        question: "Who is the only driver to win the Indy 500, NASCAR Cup Series, and Formula 1 World Championship?",
        options: ["Danica Patrick", "Juan Pablo Montoya", "Mario Andretti"],
        correctAnswer: "Juan Pablo Montoya"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the championship for professional motorcycle racing?",
        options: ["MotoGP", "World Superbike", "FIM MotoGP World Championship"],
        correctAnswer: "FIM MotoGP World Championship"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the main governing body for Formula 1?",
        options: ["FIA", "NASCAR", "FIM"],
        correctAnswer: "FIM"
      },
      {
        question: "Which event features endurance racing over 24 hours?",
        options: ["Monaco Grand Prix", "Le Mans 24 Hours", "Indy 500"],
        correctAnswer: "Le Mans 24 Hours"
      },
      {
        question: "What is the name of the series that features electric race cars?",
        options: ["Formula E", "Formula E", "IndyCar"],
        correctAnswer: "Formula E"
      },
      {
        question: "Who is known for his iconic #3 car in NASCAR?",
        options: ["Dale Earnhardt", "Richard Petty", "Jeff Gordon"],
        correctAnswer: "Dale Earnhardt"
      }
    ],
    sportsmanFact: "Niki Lauda: Austrian racing driver Niki Lauda is regarded as one of the greatest Formula 1 drivers in history. He won three World Championships and is known for his incredible comeback after a near-fatal crash in 1976. Lauda's resilience and dedication to the sport made him a beloved figure, and his story of overcoming adversity continues to inspire fans and athletes alike.",
    adviceOnLoss: "Motorsports encompass many different racing disciplines. Don't be discouraged! Watch various types of races, learn about different motorsport categories, and study famous drivers to boost your knowledge."
  }
]